Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory8 Mss.B.B61.inventory08
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Papers: Inventory (L)
1862-1942
Mss.B.B61.inventory08
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Franz Boas Papers (Mss B B61). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Scope and Contents note
Due to the size of the collection, the content for Series I has been divided into multiple inventories. Please follow the links below to browse the inventories.
Inventories
Correspondents A
Correspondents B
Correspondents C
Correspondents D
Correspondents E-G
Correspondents H
Correspondents I-K
Correspondents L
Correspondents M
Correspondents N-Q
Correspondents R
Correspondents S
Correspondents T-V
Correspondents W-Z
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents L
  - Lachateneré, Rómolo
    - See Boas, F. open letter, Feb. 6, 1941.
  - Laehr (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1927 Oct. 6; 1p.
  - La Farge, C.G. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 2; 1p.
  - La Farge, Oliver (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1931 July 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. to Villard, O.G. May 23,1939, 1939 May 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec.
  - LaFlamme, J.C.K. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1904 Mar. 14; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1904 Mar. 24; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1904 Apr. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1904 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1904 Apr. 26; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Sept. 23
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 11
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 17
    - From Boas, 1906 Nov. 19
    - From Boas, 1906 Dec. 5
    - From Boas, 1907 Mar. 2
    - From Boas, 1908 Feb. 24
    - To Boas, 1904 Mar. 5; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Mar. 20; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Apr. 25; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Sept. 22
    - To Boas, 1906 Sept. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 14; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 14
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 4
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept. 29; card
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept.; postcard
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept.; postcard
  - LaFlesche, Francis (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1928 May 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 June 23; 1p.
  - LaFollette, R.M. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1919 May 21; 1p.
  - LaFontain, H. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1912 May 20; 2p.
  - Lafrentz, Ferdinand W. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Dec. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 13; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 May 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - Lafrentz, F.W. -- from O.G. Villard, 1933 Nov. 28
  - Lagai, G. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 16; 1p.
  - Lagerlof, Selma (Box 54)
    - See Catt, C.C., Feb. 10, 1937.
  - LaGuardia, F.H. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 7; telegr.
  - Laguna, F. de (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1929 Feb. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Feb. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 16; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 May 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 May 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 June 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 4; 20p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Oct. 14; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 23; 12p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 3; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 24; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1929 May 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1929 July 21; 3p.
    - See Boas, F. to Columbia Univ. Comm. on fellowships, Feb. 27, 1930.
    - See Boas, F., Mar. 18, 1930.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Sept. 19; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Nov. 13; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec.; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 June 13; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1931 July 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Sept. 9; 8p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec.
    - To Boas, 1933 Feb. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 8; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 June 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 June; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 May 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec.; 2p.
  - Laguna, G.A. de (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Dec. 31; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Aug. 24; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 3; 3p.
  - Laguna, Theodore (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 11; 2p.
  - Laidlaw, G.E. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1918 July 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1918 July 9; 4p.
    - To Boas, undated; 1p.
    - (Answer to that of Dr. Boas of July 13, 1918)
  - Laidlaw, Harriet B. (Mrs. J.L.) (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 23; 1p.
  - Laidler, H.W. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 24; 1p.
  - Lal, G.B. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 21; 2p.
  - LaMann, J.V.K. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 21; postc.
  - Lambert, A.V.S. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1905 Feb. 24
  - Lambert, E. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1889 Oct. 9; 2p.
  - Lambert, Henri (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 10; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 19; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 9
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 16
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 21
  - Lambert, R.A. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Mar. 6; 1p.
  - Lambert, S.W. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1905 Mar. 23
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 6
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 21
    - To Boas, 1910 Mar. 26
    - S.W. Lambert -- to Emil Boas, 1915 Feb. 26
  - Lambert, W.S. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1910 Mar. 15
  - Lambot, E. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 4
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec.; 1p.
  - Lamer, H. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 15; postcard
  - Lammer?, W.W. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 4; 1p.
  - Lamont, Corliss (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - See Brewster, Dorothy, July 18, 1939.
  - Lamont, M. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1929 Mar. 18; 3p.
  - Lampell, Mina S. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1937 Jan. 26; 1p.
  - Lampert, H. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 22; 1p.
    - (Enc: Lampert, H. to Frankfurt A.M. UniversitC$t. Hohe Medizinische FakultC$t, Oct. 20, 1930)
    - H. Lampert -- to Frankfurt A.M. UniversitC$t. Hohe Medizinische FakultC$t, Oct. 20, 1930.; 2p.
  - Lampert, Kurt (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1904 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Aug. 22; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Jan. 7
  - Lamport, S.C. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1937 Mar. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 16; 1p.
  - Lancaster Press, Inc. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1926 Aug. 19; bill
  - Land, Leon R. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1938 June 29; 1p.
  - Landau, E. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept. 21; 2p.
  - Landau, Jacob (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 20; 1p.
  - Landau, Ruth (Box 54)
    - See Boas, F. (open letter), Mar. 8, 1940
  - Landauer, W. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec.
    - (See Boas, F. to Moe, H.A., 1931)
  - Lander, Joseph (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1939 May 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1939 May 2; 2p.
  - Landes, Ruth (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1934 July 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1942 Nov. 2; 1p.
  - Landman, Isaac (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1926 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 June 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 16; 1p.
  - Landry, A. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1937 June 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 June 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 July 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1937 Sept. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 May 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 June 28; 1p.
  - Landshoff, Fritz (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 4; 1p.
  - Landsteiner, K. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 17; 1p.
  - Lane, F.K. (Box 54)
    - F.K. Lane -- to N.M. Butler, 1916 Dec. 11
  - Lane, G.M. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1911 Apr. 1; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1911 May 3; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1911 May 13
    - From Boas, 1911 May 13
    - To Boas, 1911 Apr. 18
    - To Boas, 1911 May 9
  - Lane, Merritt (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1908 Dec. 2
    - To Boas, 1908 Dec. 11
  - Lane, Robert P. (Box 54)
    - R.P. Lane -- to E.P. Boas, 1942 Dec. 22; 1p.
  - Lang, R.F. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 6; 1p.
  - Langdon-Davies, J. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 6; 2p.
  - Langevin, Paul (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec.
    - See Rabkine, Louis, Notes..., Dec. 1940
    - See Urey, H.C., Jan. 3, 1941.
    - See Boas, F. open letter, Jan. 5, 1941.
  - Langley, S.P. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1889 Nov. 27
    - From Boas, 1901 May 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1902 Feb. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 3
    - To Boas, 1888 Nov. 19; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1901 May 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Feb. 14
    - To Boas, 1903 Nov. 9; postcard
    - To Boas, 1903 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Dec. 7; postcard
    - To Boas, 1904 Oct. 13
    - S.P. Langley -- to W.H. Holmes, 1903 Feb. 14; 1p.
  - Langmann, G. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Jan. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 June 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Aug. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 11; 1p.
  - Langmuir, I. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1933 May 23
    - (See Boas, F. to Wheeler, W.M., May 23, 1933)
  - Lanman, C.R. (Box 54)
    - C.R. Lanman -- from B. Laufer, 1905 Apr. 8
  - Lansing, R. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1915 Apr. 29; 2p.
    - R. Lansing -- to G.H. Tinkham, 1917 Mar. 9; 2p.
  - Lantis, M. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 12; 1p.
  - Lapie, Paul (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 1; 1p.
  - Larker, B.K. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 18
  - Larsen, Helmik (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1934 July 2; 3p.
  - Larson, Roger A. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 7; 1p.
  - Lascoff, J.L. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 18; 1p.
  - Lashley, K.S. (Box 54)
    - See Boas, F. to Woodworth, R.S., Sept. 2, 1931.
  - Lasker, B. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 23; 2p.
    - (Enc: National Conference on the Christian Way of Life. Commission on Race Relations. The social and biological effects of intermarriage in America.), 1925 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 July 12; 1p.
  - Lasker, Florina (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1936 June 12; 1p.
    - Enc. with Foss, B.J., Nov. 3, 1939.; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1939 Nov. 4; 1p.
    - (Enc. with Boas, F. to Foss, B.J., Nov. 4, 1939)
  - Latham, H.S. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 May 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 May 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 June 7; 1p.
  - Latham, W.M. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1895 Dec. 3
  - Lathe, F.E. (Box 54)
    - F.E. Lathe -- from D. Jenness, 1931 Dec. 9
  - Lathrop (Box 54)
    - From Boas
      - See Boas, F. to Cadman, S.P., May 29, 1933.
  - Lathrop, Charles G. (Box 54)
    - To Boas, 1895 Jan. 15
  - Lathrop, F.C. (Box 54)
    - See Boas, F. Open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies., Jan. 1938.
  - Lathrop, Julia C. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1912 Oct. 4
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 5; 2p.
  - Laue, M. v. (Box 54)
    - M. v. Laue -- to Nobelkomitee für Physik, 1933 Aug. 18; 2p.
  - Laufer, Berthold (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1904 July 16; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1904 Nov. 8; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 28
    - From Boas, 1906 Aug. 30
    - From Boas, 1907 Feb. 2
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 19
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 11; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1908 Oct. 21; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1908 Nov. 17
    - From Boas, 1908 Dec. 11
    - From Boas, 1909 May 5; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1911 Apr. 17; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1911 Apr. 27; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 18
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 20
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 8
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 13; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 22
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 4; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1915 Mar. 18
    - From Boas, 1915 Mar. 29; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1915 May 10; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1915 Sept. 10; 5p.
    - From Boas, 1916 Sept. 29
    - From Boas, 1916 Oct. 10
    - From Boas, 1916 Nov. 11
    - From Boas, 1916 Nov. 16
    - From Boas, 1916 Nov. 28; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1917 Jan. 8; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1917 Jan. 27
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 1
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 3
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 10
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 20
    - From Boas, 1917 May 19
    - From Boas, 1917 June 4
    - From Boas, 1917 June 8
    - From Boas, 1917 Aug. 16; 6p.
    - From Boas, 1917 Nov. 2
    - From Boas, 1917 Nov. 8
    - From Boas, 1918 Feb. 11; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Feb. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Mar. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 29; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Oct. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1918 Dec. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Mar. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Mar. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 May 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Sept. 6; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Dec. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Dec. 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1919 Dec. 22; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 May 3; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 May 10; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 July 23; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 July 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 July 30; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 21; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 5; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1922 Jan. 4; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 11; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Nov. 6; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 May 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 May 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 June 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Aug. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 June 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 June 15; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 28; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1929 Nov. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 June 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1930 June 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 27; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1900 Nov. 30; 8p.
    - To Boas, 1901 Nov. 15; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Feb. 1; 10p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Aug. 4; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Sept. 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Sept. 18; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Oct. 14; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Nov. 22; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1902 Dec. 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Feb. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Oct. 24; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Nov. 29; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1903 Dec. 4; 8p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Feb. 4; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Feb. 20; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Apr. 4; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1904 June 12; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1904 July 14; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Aug. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Aug. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Sept. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Nov. 6; 5p.
    - To Boas, 1905 July 1
    - To Boas, 1905 July 7; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1905 July 19
    - To Boas, 1905 July 26; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1905 July 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Aug. 4
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 June 27; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 June 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 July 1
    - To Boas, 1906 July 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 July 27; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 1; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 20; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 31; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 10; postcard
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 13; 8p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 20; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Dec. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1908 Dec. 6; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1909 June 6
    - To Boas, 1910 Dec. 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 7; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Apr. 12; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Apr. 15; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1911 Apr. 30; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1911 May 15
    - To Boas, 1911 May 16; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1911 July 12
    - To Boas, 1911 Oct. 19
    - To Boas, 1911 Nov. 13
    - To Boas, 1911 Nov. 29
    - To Boas, 1911 Dec. 24
    - To Boas, 1912 Aug. 26
    - To Boas, 1912 Sept. 10
    - To Boas, 1912 Sept. 26
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 5; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 14; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 20
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 22
    - To Boas, 1913 July 23; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1913 July 23
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 30; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 4
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 10
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 18
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 29
    - To Boas, 1915 Mar. 15
    - To Boas, 1915 Mar. 24
    - To Boas, 1915 Mar. 31
    - To Boas, 1915 May 14
    - To Boas, 1915 June 27
    - To Boas, 1915 Sept. 7; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1915 Sept. 15
    - To Boas, 1915 Dec. 31; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1916 Aug. 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1916 Oct. 4; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1916 Nov. 13
    - To Boas, 1916 Dec. 2
    - To Boas, 1916 Dec.; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 30
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 9
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 21
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 23
    - To Boas, 1917 May 21; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1917 May 31
    - To Boas, 1917 June 12
    - To Boas, 1917 July 31
    - To Boas, 1917 Nov. 7
    - To Boas, 1917 Nov. 8
    - To Boas, 1918 Feb. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Mar. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Mar. 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 May 4; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1918 May 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 May 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Aug. 7; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Sept. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Nov. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Nov. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 May 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 July 17; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1920 July 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 July 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 16; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Apr. 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Nov. 11; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Feb. 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 May 21; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1928 June 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 July 16; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 28; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Feb. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 25; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 June 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 14; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. to Woodworth, R.S. Sept. 2, 1931., 1931 Dec. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 2; 1p.
    - B. Laufer -- to C.E. Bodman, 1905 Jan. 20
    - B. Laufer -- to James L. Bowes, 1905 Jan. 7
    - B. Laufer -- to F.H. Chalfant, 1905 Apr. 1
    - B. Laufer -- to Walter Clark, 1905 Apr. 1
    - B. Laufer -- to Walter Clark, 1905 Apr. 27
    - B. Laufer -- to Thomas R. Clarke, 1905 Apr. 28
    - B. Laufer -- to S. Couling, 1905 Apr. 27
    - B. Laufer -- to N.H. Crossman, 1905 Apr. 11
    - B. Laufer -- to W.H. Furness 3d, 1905 Apr. 8
    - B. Laufer -- to Louis H. Gray, 1905 Jan. 25
    - B. Laufer -- to Louis H. Gray, 1905 Feb. 8
    - B. Laufer -- to Friedrich Hirth, 1905 Jan. 20
    - B. Laufer -- to E.W. Hopkins, 1904 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - B. Laufer -- to E.W. Hopkins, 1905 Apr. 3
    - B. Laufer -- to Thomas E. Kirby, 1905 Jan. 11
    - B. Laufer -- to Thomas E. Kirby, 1905 Jan. 23
    - B. Laufer -- to C.R. Lanman, 1905 Apr. 8
    - B. Laufer -- to Luzac & Co., 1905 Apr. 23
    - B. Laufer -- to Mrs. Alex. Lyall, 1904 Dec. 17; 2p.
    - B. Laufer -- to William McAdoo, 1904 Nov. 28; 1p.
    - B. Laufer -- to Arthur Michael, 1905 Jan. 25
    - B. Laufer -- to F.W. Putnam, 1905 Apr. 28
    - B. Laufer -- to H. Putnam, 1917 May 26; 2p.
    - B. Laufer -- from Gutenberg-Haus Franz Franke, 1898 Feb. 3
    - B. Laufer -- to W.W. Rockhill, 1905 Mar. 23
    - B. Laufer -- from J.H. Schiff, 1911 May 8
    - B. Laufer -- to F.W. Thomas, 1905 Jan. 11
    - B. Laufer -- to J.H. Wheeler, 1905 Jan. 25
    - B. Laufer -- to R.H. Williams, 1905 Jan. 30
    - B. Laufer -- to C. Wissler, 1920 Nov. 13; 3p.
    - B. Laufer -- to H.C. Wright, 1905 Apr. 11
  - Laughlin, Harry H. (Box 54)
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 20; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 June 28; 1p.
      Scope and Contents note
      (Enc: Papers for Third International Congress of eugenics.)
    - To Boas, 1918 Apr. 18; 1p.
  - Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial
    - To Boas, 1926 June; 3p.
    - From Institute for Comparative Research in Human Culture, 1925 Oct. 7
    - From Stang, F., 1926 Apr. 12
  - Lauterbach, Edward (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 16; 1p.
  - Laves, Kurt (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 13; 1p.
  - Lavit, J.P. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 9
  - Lawent?, G.L. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 15; 1p.
  - Lawrence, W.M. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 27; 2p.
  - Lawrence, W.W. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 23; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Apr. 8; 1p.
  - Lawson, F.C. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 18; 1p.
  - Lawson, J.H. (Box 55)
    - J.H. Lawson -- to O.G. Villard, 1934 Dec. 30; 2p.
  - Lawson, Leonard A. (Box 55)
    - See Boas, F. Open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies., Jan. 1938.
  - Lawton, G.L. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1932 Nov. 14; 1p.
      (Enc: Summary)
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 30; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 20; 1p.
  - Lazarus, H.P. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1935 May 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Apr. 18; 6p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Apr. 28; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1935 May 11; 1p.
  - Leach, Henry G. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 11; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Apr. 10; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Apr. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Sept. 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 6; 1p.
  - League of American Writers (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1939 June 1; 1p.
  - League of Nations (Box 55)
    - To The Council and members of the League, 1922 Nov. 4
      See Bergson, M.H.
  - Leahy, W.W. (Box 55)
    - To Boas, 1929 Dec.; 1p.
  - Leale, Lillian (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1936 June 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 May 30; 1p.
  - Learned M.D. (Box 55)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 17; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - See Boas, F. to Francke, K. Nov. 28,1905, 1905 Dec. 19; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 24; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 3; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 6; 1p.